What is a jerk minimizing trajectory?
什么是一条 “jerk minimizing” 轨迹？
An interesting and useful fact to us is that it is
对我们而言 一个有趣并有用的事实是
relatively easy to compute a jerk optimal trajectory in one dimension.
在单个维度上计算一条 Jerk 优化的轨迹是相对容易的
In fact, consider a function s of t different from time zero to time tf.
事实上 考虑一个有关时间 t 的函数 s 从时间点0到 tf
and recall that jerk is a third relative of position.
并且回想一下 jerk 是与位置相关的第三个参数
So the total jerk accumulated over
所以在沿着这条轨迹行驶过程中累计的总 jerk 量
the duration of this trajectory is given by this equation.
由这个等式确定
And here, we want to analyze both positive and negative jerk.
这里 我们想要分析正面的和负面的 jerk
Therefore, we're going to look at total square jerk.
因此 我们将要看看总的直角 jerk
Our problem is then to find a function s of t that minimizes this integral.
我们的问题是 找出一个函数 s 该函数最小化这个成份
If we go through the math required to find the minimum,
如果我们查看与找出最小值相关的数学上的东西
you'll find that all the time derivatives of s of order
大家会发现 如果要让 s 成为 jerk 最小化的
six and more have to be zero in order for S to be jerk minimal.
那么 s 的所有时间导数必须为0
Now, we can also use a helpful fact about functions,
现在 我们可以应用一个有关函数的非常有用的特性
which is that any function can be written like this or more compactly like this.
那就是 所有函数可以写成这样 或者更简洁地写成这样
When you take this form of s and add in
如果我们把 s 写成这样
the information that we have about it's time derivative, you find this.
并且加入我们已知的它的时间导数 那么结果是这样
All of the coefficient bigger than five or zero,
所有的系数都大于5 或者为0
which means that all minimum jerk trajectories
这意味着所有的 jerk 最小化轨迹
can be represented as a fifth order polynomial like this.
都可以表示为一个这样的5次多项式
You can see this equation has six coefficients and six coefficients means
大家可以看到 这个等式有6个系数
six tuneable parameters that we can choose
6个系数意味着6个可调参数
from in order to define the shape of a 1D trajectory.
我们可以使用这些参数来定义某个一维轨迹的形状
And in practice, we use them to specify the boundary conditions of our trajectory.
事实上 我们使用它们来指定轨迹的边界条件
The things we'd like to constrain are the initial position, velocity,
我们想要将约束的对象包括 最初位置 速度 加速度
and acceleration as well as the final position, velocity and acceleration.
以及 最终位置 速度 加速度
Now, this is just the 1D representing the longitude of displacement.
现在 这只是纵向移动的一维展示
But, the same for the lateral displacement applies.
但是 横向移动同样适用
This gives us 12 variables to pick in order to fully
这样 我们就有了12个变量
define the motion of our vehicle in S&amp;D over time.
来完整定义车辆随时间的运动
The initial state of our vehicle give us
我们车辆的最初状态
the longitudinal and lateral boundary conditions t equals zero,
纵向和横向边界条件 t 等于 0
and we get to pick the end boundary condition.
我们也可以选择最终的边界条件
I'm going to show you plots of what lateral trajectories look like for a simple case,
我会向大家展示一个小例子 显示出横向轨迹是什么样子的
where a car moves from here to here and make
这里 一辆车从这里移动到这里
the simplifying assumption that
我们做个简化
the initial and final lateral velocities and accelerations are zero.
假定最初和最终横向速度和加速度均为0
Which is reasonable for lane change.
这在变道操作中是合理的
Then, all boundary conditions look like this.
然后 所有的边界条件看起来是这样的
And the only nonzero quantity of this 1D problem is the final lateral displacement.
这里唯一的非零值是最终的横向位移
Let's look at what some of these trajectories look like.
我们继续看一些此类轨迹
Keep in mind, this is a one dimensional motion.
记住 这是一个一维运动
The X axis here is time and
X 轴代表时间
the Y axis is lateral position of the vehicle as it makes its lane change.
Y 轴代表车辆在变道时候的横向位置
The F and T are the final lateral displacements and the duration of our trajectory.
F 代表最终横向位移 T 代表轨迹的持续时间
You can see at equal zero,
大家可以看到 在0时刻
the position is zero.
位置值为0
The slope is zero so velocity is now and so is acceleration.
坡度为0 所以速度和加速度也为0
Likewise, for the final position that equals 10.
同样地 在最后为10的位置
And this curves looks pretty smooth.
这条曲线看起来非常平滑
But let's also look at velocity over time and acceleration over time.
但是 现在我们看看速度和加速度随时间的变化情况
Although not all of these curves might be meaningful to you,
虽然并非所有这些曲线大家都能看明白
let's think back about what just happened here.
大家来回想一下 刚才我们都做了些什么
We've specified a position we wanted to reach and a time we wanted to
在一些方程式中 我们指定了一个目标位置 指定了一个到达时间
reach it at in some equations and we end up with a nice looking trajectory.
最后 我们得出了一条看起来很不错的轨迹
It's very nice indeed because a lot of drivers would not attain
这条轨迹的确非常棒 如果你请一些司机沿着这条轨迹行驶
that level of comfort if we were to ask them to reproduce it.
很多人并不能行驶得和轨迹完全吻合
Now, let's see what happens if I try to reach the destinations more
现在 如果我们想更快到达目的地 因此我们把时间值 T 调小
quickly by turning down T. Sure enough,
我们来看一下 会发生什么情况
we can still find the trajectory over time,
当然 我们仍然可以得到一条轨迹
but it's much more jerky.
但是它会非常颠簸
It is important to realize that although the trajectory that we generate
有一点非常重要 尽管我们使用 Jerk优化法加一些边界条件
using this method or jerk optimal for a given set of boundary conditions,
生成了轨迹
they still depend heavily on these conditions.
它们仍然重度依赖于这些条件
Therefore, it would be important in the future to wisely pick these end conditions.
因此 在未来 明智地选择这些最终条件是非常重要的
Now, I want to show you how I computed what
现在 我将向大家展示
the six coefficient had to be in order to satisfy these boundary conditions.
我是如何计算6个系数以满足这些边界条件的